A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 17727-19980 FA739G
Rockefeller Archive Center
- India: The Foundation's program in agriculture and rural development (Reports 018418) (AG 75-3), 1975; Bailey, Charles R. (Charles Randall), 1938- (Box 935, Sheet AG 75-3)
- Summary of RAPRAP: agenda for future research-and-development (Reports 018419) (AG 76-4), 1976; Bailey, Charles R. (Charles Randall), 1938- (Box 935, Sheet AG 76-4)
- Local level rural institutions (Reports 018420) (AG 76-9), 1976; Reynolds, Norman, 1934- (Box 935, Sheet AG 76-9)
  Agriculture and state -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India; Rural development -- India
- The relevance of anthropology to development planning and research (Reports 018421) (AG 76-11), 1976; Mailloux, Laurel D. (Box 935, Sheet AG 76-11)
- Report to Dr. Mailloux (Reports 018422) (AG 76-12), 1976; Petit, Michel, 1936- (Box 935, Sheet AG 76-12)
- Consultancy report (Reports 018423) (AG 76-13), 1976; Johnson, Glenn (Box 935, Sheet AG 76-13)
- Cinq semaines a Sapnawat - l'equilibre precaire d'une societe villageoise de la plaine du Gange, Kharif (Reports 018424) (AG 76-14), 1976; Sorba, Alain; Carmine, Brigitte (Box 935, Sheet AG 76-14)
- Models of resource management in Asia: the entry of demographic thought (Reports 018425) (AG 78-2), 1978; Romm, Jeff (Box 935, Sheet AG 78-2)
  International Seminar on Population and Development, Colombo, Sri Lanka, December 11-15, 1978.
  Agriculture and state -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India; Resources management -- India
- Choice of irrigation techniques under alternative physical and socio-economic conditions (Reports 018426) (AG 78-3), 1978; Lenton, R. L.; Seckler, David William, 1935- (Box 935, Sheet AG 78-3)
  Presented at the sixteenth annual convention of the Indian Society of Agricultural engineers at the Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur, December 18-20, 1978.
  Agriculture and state -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India; Irrigation -- India; Agricultural innovations -- India
- SUKHOMAJRI - a rural development program in India (Reports 018427) (AG 79-4), 1979; Seckler, David William, 1935- (Box 935, Sheet AG 79-4)
  Appendix-I on economic evaluation of the Sukhomajri project 11 p.
- Food policy: production and consumption issues aspects of agricultural research for production (Reports 018428) (AG 79-6), 1979; Collins, Norman R.; Dagg, Matthew (Box 935, Sheet AG 79-6)
  Group I, food policy: consumption and production issues A7P agricultural and resources staff seminar.
  Agriculture and state -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India; Food production -- India
- Towards improved models for field experimentation in irrigation management (Reports 018429) (AG 79-8), 1979; Lenton, R. L. (Box 935, Sheet AG 79-8)
  Resource paper - group II - irrigation development projects: experimentation and implementation, Asia and Pacific agricultural and resource staff seminar.
- Towards a research agenda for social forestry (Reports 018430) (AG 80-1), 1980; Romm, Jeff (Box AG 80-1, Sheet AG 80-1)
  Agriculture and state -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India; Forest and forestry -- India
- Water resources management: some thoughts on interdisciplinary research (Reports 018431) (AG 80-2), 1980; Lenton, R. L. (Box 935, Sheet AG 80-2)
  IHD Endowment lecture - Indian National Committee for the IHD-Centre for Water Resources, Peraringar Anna University of Technology.
  Agriculture and state -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India; Water management -- India; Irrigation -- India
- Field experimentation and generalization in irrigation development and management (Reports 018432) (AG 80-2a), 1980; Lenton, R. L. (Box 935, Sheet AG 80-2a)
- Management agencies for rural development (Reports 018433) (AG 81-2), 1981; Seckler, David William, 1935- (Box 935, Sheet AG 81-2)
- Management of social forestry programs: a prospectus (Reports 018434) (AG 81-3), 1981; Seckler, David William, 1935- (Box 935, Sheet AG 81-3)
- The wastelands development corporation: a prospectus (Reports 018435) (AG 81-4), 1981; Seckler, David William, 1935- (Box 935, Sheet AG 81-4)
- Summer project report on social forestry management (Reports 018436) (AG 83-2), 1983; Shyam, Pita (Box 935, Sheet AG 83-2)
- Analysis of means for providing adequate office space for Ford Foundation headquarters (mimeo), New Delhi, India (Reports 018437) (GE 64-1), 1964 (Box 936, Sheet GE 64-1)
  India reports;General
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Office management -- India
- A glimmer of light (Reports 018438) (GE 65-2), 1965; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 936, Sheet GE 65-2)
  Commencement address at Orissa University of Agriculture and Technology, Bhubaneshwar.
- Report on the administrative procedures of the Ford Foundation Calcutta and Kathmandu offices (mimeo) (Reports 018439) (GE 65-3), 1965; Sikka, R. G. (Box 936, Sheet GE 65-3)
- Guide for testing new grant proposals and procedure for grant development (mimeo) (Reports 018440) (GE 66-1), 1966; Hill, Rey M. (Box 936, Sheet GE 66-1)
- All India staff conference - October 24-25, 1966 - minutes of conference (mimeo) (Reports 018441) (GE 66-4) (Box 936, Sheet GE 66-4)
- The social and personal significance of housing (mimeo), Ocotober (Reports 018442) (GE 66-8), 1966; Willey, Malcolm M. (Malcolm Macdonald), 1897-1974 (Box 936, Sheet GE 66-8)
  An address delivered at the eighth biennial conference of the Home Science Association of India, Calcutta.
  Housing -- India
- Proceedings of the Ford Foundation India staff conference (mimeo) (Reports 018443) (GE 66-12), 1966 (Box 936, Sheet GE 66-12)
- Lodi park master plan (mimeo) (Reports 018444) (GE 67-6a), 1967; Eckbo, Garrett; Stein, Joseph Allen, 1912-2001 (Box 936, Sheet GE 67-6a)
  Preliminary report prepared for the city of New Delhi.
  Community development, Urban -- India; City planning -- India
- Regarding GOI's plan to invite Ford Foundation for eight high priority projects (mimeo) (Reports 018445) (GE 67-6b), 1967; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 887, Box 936, Sheet GE 67-6b)
  Community development, Urban -- India
- Attachment I - areas of past Foundation assistance (mimeo) (Reports 018446) (GE 67-6c), 1967 (Box 936, Sheet GE 67-6c)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- India
- Attachment II - areas being considered for future Foundation assistance (mimeo) (Reports 018447) (GE 67-6c), 1967 (Box 936, Sheet GE 67-6d)
- New Programs (mimeo) (Reports 018448) (GE 67-6d), 1966; Ensminger, Douglas, 1910-1989 (Box 936, Sheet GE 67-6d)
- Memorandum - New York-Delhi interaction (mimeo) (Reports 018449) (GE 67-8), 1967; Kieloch, Edward A., 1928- (Box 936, Sheet GE 67-8)
- A brief account of life in Thanjavur (mimeo) (Reports 018450) (GE 67-9), 1967 (Box 936, Sheet GE 67-9)
- Background information for use in public presentations describing the Ford Foundation and its overseas development program (mimeo) (Reports 018451) (GE 67-13), 1967 (Box 936, Sheet GE 67-13)
- Special prevue - Ford Foundation headquarters buildings, New Delhi (mimeo) (Reports 018452) (GE 68-7), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet GE 68-7)
- Quarterly letter - the Ford Foundation India and Nepal (mimeo) (Reports 018453) (GE 68-9, GE 68-11), 1968 January, December (Box 887, Box 936, Sheet GE 68-9, Sheet GE 68-11)
  Community development -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India
- Handbook for Indian administrative services staff (mimeo) (Reports 018454) (GE 68-13), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet GE 68-13)
- The Lodi park master plan proposal - for the city of New Delhi (Reports 018455) (GE 68-14), 1968 (Box 887, Box 936, Sheet GE 68-14)
- Use on Indian nationals as Ford Foundation staff consultants to Indian institutional clients (mimeo) (Reports 018456) (GE 68-15), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet GE 68-15)
- A survey on the wage and salary structure of the Indian field office of the Ford Foundation (mimeo) (Reports 018457) (GE 70-5), 1970; Sarbjit Singh (Box 936, Sheet GE 70-5)
- Independent study (mimeo) (Reports 018458) (GE 72-1), 1972; Weisblat, Tinky (Box 936, Sheet GE 72-1)
  Ford Foundation -- India
- The Ford Foundation, India, Nepal and Sri Lanka (Reports 018459) (GE 75-1), 1975 (Box 936, Sheet GE 75-1)
- Politics in Bihar: some observations (mimeo) (Reports 018460) (GE 78-1), 1978; Pande, Vijay G. (Box 936, Sheet GE 78-1)
  Ford Foundation -- India; India -- Politics and government
- Bihar's economic and resource status (mimeo) (Reports 018461) (GE 78-2), 1978; Sampath, Rajan K. (Rajan Kasturi), 1948- (Box 936, Sheet GE 78-2)
  Economic conditions -- India; Economic aspects -- India
- Bihar's land tenure system - its effects on agricultural development (mimeo) (Reports 018462) (GE 78-3), 1978; Sundar, Pushpa (Box 936, Sheet GE 78-3)
  Economic aspects -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India
- Gangetic basin: notes on resource management issues (mimeo) (Reports 018463) (GE 78-4), 1978; Collins, Norman R.; Dagg, Matthew (Box 936, Sheet GE 78-4)
  Economic aspects -- India; Agricultural development projects -- India; Resource management -- India
- Ford Foundation: Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program (Reports 018464), 2004
  To articulate the aspirations and values behind this restructured program, we decided to rename our Education, Media, Arts and Culture program Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom and craft a new statement communicating our sense of the context in which we w
  Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom program 2004
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Management; Education; Mass media; Arts
- Fundacion Ford: programa conocimiento, creatividad y libertad (Reports 018465), 2004
  Spanish translation of Ford Foundation: Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom
- Inclusive scholarship: a 25th anniversary retrospective of Ford Foundation grantmaking, 1982 - 2007 (Reports 018466), Harris, Robert L.; Hine, Darlene Clark; McKay, Nellie Y.; O'Meally, Robert G., 1948-; Smith, Valerie; Yarborough, Richard Alan; Pinderhughes, Dianne M. (Dianne Marie), 1947-; Griffin, Farah Jasmine
  This volume brings together four decisive reports, the first by Nathan I. Huggins, the second by Robert L. Harris Jr., Darlene Clark Hine and Nellie McKay, the third by Robert G. O'Meally and Valerie Smith and the final by Dianne M. Pinderhughes and Richa
  Afro-American studies programs -- Evaluation; African Americans -- Study and teaching -- United States;Teaching and scholarship
- Strategies for improving public education: a Foundation returns to school (Reports 018467), 2008
  A grant maker's reflections on our Constituency Building for Public School Reform initiative. The 13-year effort helped build coalitions of informed constituents to collaborate and mobilize to bring about needed changes in public schools.
  School improvement programs -- United States; Public schools -- United States; Education -- Government policy -- United States; Education -- United States -- Finance -- Legal aspects; School management and organization -- United States
- Pathways to higher education: a Ford Foundation global initiative for promoting inclusiveness in higher education (Reports 018468), 2008
  Case studies of how universities worldwide are aiding marginalized groups to enroll and graduate.
  Education, Higher -- Aims and objectives; Universities and colleges -- Evaluation; Universities and colleges -- Admission; Universities and colleges -- Educational equalization
- Report to the Ford Foundation on Crossing Borders: revitalizing area studies (1997-2002) (Reports 018469), Navarro, Marysa; Mohanty, Chandra Talpade, 1955- (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom/Media Arts and Culture
  Crossing borders: revitalizing area studies
  Area studies -- Endowments; Foreign study -- Endowments; Social sciences -- Research; International education; Endowments -- Evaluation; Crossing Borders (Program)
- Preliminary assessment of the impact of HIV/AIDS on afro-descendant populations of the Americas (Reports 018470), 2006 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  "From the very beginning of the AIDS epidemic in the United States (U.S.) the Centres for Disease Control (CDC) and other agencies have noted a disproportionate impact on people of color, and in particular on the African-American population. Whereas in 19
  Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom/Education, Sexuality, and Religion
  AIDS (Disease) -- United States; AIDS (Disease) -- Latin America; HIV infections -- United States; HIV infections -- Latin America; African Americans -- Health and hygiene; Latin Americans -- Health and hygiene
- Reflection memo (Reports 018471), 2007; Abregu, Martin (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This Representative's Reflection Memo is the first of its kind for the Andean Region and Southern Cone.[]Abregu became the Representative of the Andean Region and Southern Cone office based in Santiago, Chile in September 2007.
  Human Rights and Governance
  Human rights -- South America; Reproductive health -- South America; Civil rights -- South America; Human rights -- South America
- Reflection memo (Reports 018472), 2004; Ahonsi, Babatunde (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memo prepared by Babatunde Ahonsi on West Africa's sexuality and reproductive health portfolio, with evaluation of international policy on reproductive health and key global problems, such as disease and environmental crises.
  Peace and Social Justice
  Women's rights -- Africa; Reproductive health -- Africa; Gender discrimination -- Africa; Human rights -- Africa; Ford Foundation. Peace and Social Justice
- Reflection memo (Reports 018473), 2002; Anthony, Carl (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)/Community and Resource Development
  Urbanization -- United States; Poverty -- Social aspects -- United States; Race discrimination -- Environment -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018474), 2003; Anthony, Carl (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Urbanization -- United States; Poverty -- Social aspects -- United States; Race discrimination -- United States; Poverty -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018475), 2004; Anthony, Carl (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018476), 2005; Anthony, Carl (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This memorandum is a reflection on the key trends in fields related to the Sustainable Metropolitan Communities Initiative and the Regional Equity Demonstrations during FY '05. The Memo covers accomplishments and key challenges for each of the initiatives
- Reflection memo (Reports 018477), 2000; Antlov, Hans (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Peace and Social Justice/Governance and Civil Society
  Political participation -- Indonesia; Civil society -- Indonesia; Democracy -- Indonesia; Decentralization in government -- Indonesia; Endowments -- Indonesia -- Evaluation
- Reflection memo (Reports 018478), 2001; Antlov, Hans (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Political participation -- Indonesia; Civil society -- Indonesia; Democracy -- Indonesia; Endowments -- Indonesia -- Evaluation
- Reflection memo (Reports 018479), 2002; Antlov, Hans (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018480), 2003; Antlov, Hans (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018481), 2004; Antlov, Hans (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018482), 2006; Bagwell, Orlando (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memo prepared by Orlando Bagwell outlining aspects of digital information technology, as it pertains to media, arts and culture.
  Digital information resources; Public television -- United States; Mass media -- Censorship; Mass media -- Social aspects
- Reflection memo (Reports 018483), 2003; Bailey, Charles R. (Charles Randall), 1938- (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memo prepared by Charles Bailey of the Office for Vietnam, outlining portfolio's success in working with Vietnamese officials toward furthering the initiative goals.
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)/Peace and Social Justice
  Reflection Memo
  Education -- Vietnam; Endowment of research
- Reflection memo (Reports 018484), 2004; Bailey, Charles R. (Charles Randall), 1938- (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018485), 2006; Bain, Irene (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This Reflection Memo documents the key activities, progress, challenges and insights which have emerged during FY 2006 within this expanding portfolio and the context of the changing situation in China.
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)
  Forestry -- China; Community and forestry; Environmental accountability; Grasslands -- China -- Management; Environmental aspects; Ethnic diversity -- China; Natural resources -- Conservation; Poverty -- China
- Reflection memo (Reports 018486), 2007; Bain, Irene (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This Reflection Memo documents the key activities, progress, challenges and insights which have emerged during FY 2007 within this expanding portfolio and the context of the changing situation in China.
- Reflection memo (Reports 018487), 2007; Balachander, Ganesan (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  The author came into the New Delhi office in mid-2003 at a time when two of the portfolios were being closed the Human Rights portfolio in PSJ and Environmental Justice in the Assets program. The reflection covers the three plus years since then and loo
  Forestry -- Social aspects -- India; Natural resources -- Management -- India
- Reflection memo (Reports 018488), 2001; Barry, Deborah (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Economic development -- Mexico; Economic development -- Central America; Microfinance -- Mexico; Microfinance -- Central America; Endowments -- Mexico -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Central America -- Evaluation; Forest conservation -- Central America; Land management
- Reflection memo (Reports 018489), 2003; Barry, Deborah (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Economic development -- Mexico; Economic development -- Central America; Endowments -- Mexico -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Central America -- Evaluation; Forest conservation -- Central America; Land management -- Central America; Payment Schemes for Ecosystem Services (PES)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018490), 2004; Barry, Deborah (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Economic development -- Mexico; Economic development -- Central America; Endowments -- Mexico -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Central America -- Evaluation; Forest conservation -- Central America; Land management -- Central America
- Reflection memo (Reports 018491), 2003; Berrien, Jacqueline A. (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Throughout FY 2003, but especially during the final quarter of the fiscal year, the U.S. Presidential campaign emerged as the political event generating the most consistent and extensive news coverage. The author identifies a number of defining features o
  Democracy -- United States; Citizen participation -- United States; Pluralism (Social sciences); Ford Foundation. Peace and Social Justice
- Reflection memo (Reports 018492), 2001; Brown, Kimberli Keith (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Governance and Civil Society
  Civil society -- Mexico; Civil society -- Central America
- Reflection memo (Reports 018493), 2002; Iskandar, Meiwita Budiharsana (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This memo reflects on Sexuality and Reproductive Health work at the Jakarta office of the Foundation, covering the period from August 2001 to September 30, 2002.
  Health services for women; Reproductive health; Women -- Indonesia -- Economic aspects; HIV/AIDS; Sexually transmitted diseases
- Reflection memo (Reports 018494), 2006; Butler-Adam, J. F. (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memo prepared by John Butler-Adam evaluating the higher education portfolio in Southern Africa.
  Education, Higher -- Aims and objectives -- Africa; Education and state -- Africa; Education -- Curricula -- Africa
- Reflection memo (Reports 018495), 2002; Conroy, Michael E. (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Community development -- United States; Natural resources -- United States -- Management; Forestry and community -- United States; Forest management -- United States; Forestry projects -- United States; Economic development; Environment -- Development -- Research
- Reflection memo (Reports 018497), 2004; Cook, Sarah, 1961- (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Political planning -- China; Local government -- China; Civil society -- China
- Reflection memo (Reports 018498), 2004; Campbell, J. Y. (Jeffrey Y.) (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memo prepared by Jeffrey Campbell, evaluating state of donor interest in community forestry, and overview of program initiatives to date.
  Forests and forestry -- Economic aspects -- United States; Natural resources -- Economic aspects -- United States; Natural resources -- Conservation -- United States
- Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom reflection memos: Worldwide Meeting: November 13 -20, 2005, Johannesburg, South Africa (Reports 018499) (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memos on Knowledge, Creativity & Freedom program for 2005.[]KC&F staff: A. Bernstein, David Chiel, Janice Petrovich, Jorge Balan, Constance H. Buchanan, Cyrus Driver, Ondina Fachel Leal, Chris Martin, Barbara Klugman, Maria Amelia Palacios, Galina Rakhmanova, Carla Sutherland, Margaret B. Wilkerson, Orlando Blackw
  Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom
  Human rights -- South Africa -- Congresses; Congresses and conventions -- South Africa; Apartheid -- Africa -- Congresses
- Reflection memo (Reports 018500), 2000; Davie, Fred (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Religious institutions -- Social aspects -- United States; Community development -- Religion; Problem youth -- Rehabilitation -- United States -- Religion; African American youth -- Religious life
- Reflection memo (Reports 018501), 2007; DeGiovanni, Frank F. (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Workforce -- United States; Economic conditions -- United States; Poor -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018502), 2002; DiGregorio, Michael R., 1955- (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Education -- Vietnam
- Reflection memo (Reports 018503), 2003; DiGregorio, Michael R., 1955- (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018504), 2006; DiGregorio, Michael R., 1955- (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018505), 2007; DiGregorio, Michael R., 1955- (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018506), 2006; Dora, Denise Dourado (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This reflection memo covers the Human Rights Program activities in Fiscal Year 2006 (from October 2005 to September 2006).[]Memo to Ana Toni, dated September 20, 2006.
  Peace and Social Justice/Human Rights and International Cooperation
  Human rights -- Brazil; Race discrimination -- Brazil; Sex discrimination -- Brazil; Endowments -- Brazil -- Evaluation
- Reflection memo (Reports 018507), 2002; Driver, Cyrus (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memo prepared by Cyrus Driver evaluating the challenges raised concerning K-12 and community college reform, seen in connection with racial and social inequalities.
  Education, Higher -- United States; Racial discrimination -- Social aspects -- United States; People with social disadvantages -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018508), 2003; Driver, Cyrus (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018509), 2004; Driver, Cyrus (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This portfolio has evolved greatly the past six years to reflect my views on effective strategies to institutionalize large-scale improvements in the quality of urban public schools and community college systems. Strategies have focused on three dimension
- Reflection memo (Reports 018510), 2006; Driver, Cyrus (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018511), 2007; Edwards, Michael, 1957- (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Governance and Civil Society/Peace and Social Justice
  Political participation -- Iraq; Civil society -- Iraq; Political participation -- China; Civil society -- China
- Reflection memo (Reports 018512), 2002; Eguizabal, Cristina (Box 888, Reel R-9324)